New England Hospital for Women and Children Records, 1792-1994
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES I. HISTORY 1859-1994
  - Publications
    - The Hospital Visitor, Dec 1887 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Reports
    - Annual
      - 1864-1903 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
      - 1863-87 (1st to 25th) (bound volume) (Box 3)
      - 1904-10 (incomplete) (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1911-23 (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
      - 1924-28 (incomplete) (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - 1919-32 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - 1933-39 (incomplete) (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - 1940-56 (incomplete) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1878-1920, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Photographs
    - New England Hospital and related personnel, 1839-1962 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Eminent people, 1839, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook (clippings), 1953-55 (Box 7)
- SERIES II. PERSONNEL 1868-1963
  - Physicians
    - Minutes of the physicians meetings, 1876-1917 (8v) (Box 8)
    - Reports of Medical board and physicians meetings, 1876-1915 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Bigelow, Alice, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Brunner-Orne, Martha Brunner, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Cooper, Gladys A., 1915 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Dimock, Susan, 1868-73, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Memoir of Susan Dimock, Resident Physician of the New England Hospital for Women and Children (Boston, 1875) (2 copies) (Box 9)
    - Van Hoosen, Bertha, 1891 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Zakrzewska, Marie E.
      - Biographical articles, speeches, and correspondence, 1859-1963, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Portrait donations, 1887 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - A Woman's Quest, The Life of Marie E. Zakrzewska, M.D. by Agnes C. Vietor (New York, D. Appleton), 1924 (Box 9)
      - A Practical Illustration of "Woman's Right To Labor;" or, A letter from Marie E. Zakrzewska, M.D. edited by Caroline Dall (Boston, Walker, Wise &#38; Co.), 1860 (Box 9)
  - Nurses
    - Mahoney, Mary, 1879-1954, undated, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Richards, Linda, 1911-41 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Simpson, Bessie H. 1904 (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
  - Interns, [see Appendix I for alphabetical list]
    - Lists of former interns and numbers of applicants, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1891-92, A-C (Box 10)
    - 1892-99 (Box 10, Folder 2-8)
    - 1900-02 (Box 11, Folder 1-8)
    - 1903-05 (Box 12, Folder 1-7)
    - 1906-08 (Box 13, Folder 1-7)
    - 1909-12 (Box 14, Folder 1-9)
    - 1913-16 (Box 15, Folder 1-8)
    - 1917-26 (Box 16, Folder 1-9)
- SERIES III. FINANCIAL 1860-1920
  - Finance Committee minutes and reports, 1877-1915, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS (fund drive poster)] (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Clark, Edward L., 1899-1900 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Cheney, Ednah Dow, 1881-1900 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Crawford, Sarah, 1879 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Farnam, Emily E., 1889 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - May, Fred W.G., 1883 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Pope, Augusta, 1899, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Pope, Charlotte, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Richards, Linda, 1893 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Zakrzewska, Marie E., 1878-1905 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1877-1910 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Bills, 1860-1920 (Box 17, Folder 12-14)
- SERIES IV. CORRESPONDENCE 1847-1928
  - A, 1885-1918 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - B, 1878-1914 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Butler, Emma E., 1894-99, 1909 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - C, 1885-1920 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Call, Emma L., 1887-1919 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Cheney, Ednah Dow
    - Outgoing
      - Board of Directors on death of Samuel Cabot, 1885 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Channing, Eva, 1884-1902, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Channing, Susan B., 1852-92, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous, 1860-82 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Incoming, 1847-90, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Condolence letters, 1885-1920 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Culbertson, Emma B., 1882-98 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - D - E, 1892-1911 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Emerson, Adele, 1916 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - F, 1885-1920 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Farnham, Ellen, 1882-98 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - G, 1884-1920 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - H, 1885-1920 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Hamilton, Alice, 1894 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Hamilton, Annie Lee, 1900-17 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - I - J, 1886-1920 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Jacobi, M. Putnam, 1892, 1906 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Jones, Alfred, 1897, 1904 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - K, 1875-1920 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Kellogg, Helen R., 1889-90 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Kyle Frances E., 1890, undated (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - L, 1891-1919 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Lathrop, Harriet E., 1890-1900 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - M, 1890-1922 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous, 1861-63 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - N - O, 1901-20 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - P, 1885-1917 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Palmer, Sarah E., 1896-1915 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Pope, C. Augusta, 1882-1919 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Pope, Emily F., 1878-1928 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - R, 1883-1920 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - S, 1879-1917 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - T, 1883-1919 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Taylor, Stella M., 1894-1918 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - V, 1889-1904 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - W, 1885-1920 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - White, Frances Emily, 1903 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - XYZ, 1904-08 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Zakrzewska, Marie E., 1878-92 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- SERIES V. SUBJECTS 1876-1963
  - Abortion, 1915 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Chloroform, 1888 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - African-American women interns, 1911 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Nurses examinations, 1894 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Rules and regulations, 1876-1914 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Tufts Medical School (affiliation in obstetrics), 1913-14 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Women's Hospital, Philadelphia, Training School for Nurses, 1878 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- SERIES VI. AUTOGRAPH COLLECTION 1792-1905, 2 linear ft.
  - Letters
    - Abbott, Francis E., 1872-89 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Abbott, John C., 1871 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Adams, Charles Francis, 1873-80 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Adams, E., 1884 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Adams, L. H., undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Adams, William T. ("Oliver Optic"), 1872 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Adler, Felix, 1880 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Agassiz, Alexander, 1886 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Alcott, A. Bronson, 1869-82 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Alcott, Louisa May, 1882-88, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Alcott, May, 1876 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Aldrich, Thomas Bailey, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Allen, Joseph Henry, 1867 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Ames, Charles, 1896 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Ames, Fanny, 1893 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Ames, Isaac, 1873 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Ames, Oakes, 1870 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Anagnos, Julia and Michael, 1877-95, undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Andrew, John A., 1861 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Anthony, Susan B., 1888-95, undated (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Apthorp, R.E., 1873 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Arbuthnot, Margaret Evelyn, 1895 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Armstrong, Samuel Chapman, 1876 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Arthur, Kendall, 1882 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Atkinson, W.P., 1879 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Audubon, Lucy (Mrs. J.J.), 1873 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Babcock, William, 1855-91 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Badger, Ada S., 1873 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Balgarnie, Florence, 1891 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Bancroft, George, 1862 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Bancroft, Herbert Howe, 1883 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Barba, Noyes, 1835 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Barrett, Lawrence, 1875 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Barrows, Isabel C. and S.J., 1888-89 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Bartlett, George B., 1889, undated (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Barton, Clara, 1883 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Beecher, Henry Ward, 1869, undated (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Benjamin, Samuel Greene Wheeler, 1887 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Biggs, Caroline Ashurst, undated (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Bissell, Helen W., 1890 (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - Black, E. Charlton, 1893 (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - Blackie, John S., 1878 (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - Blackwell Alice Stone, 1886-1903 (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - Blackwell, Elizabeth, 1848, 1887, undated (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - Blackwell, Emily, 1895 (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Blackwell, Hannah, undated (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - Blackwell, Henry Brown, 1888-1902 (Box 21, Folder 47)
    - Blind, Mathilde, 1885, undated (Box 21, Folder 48)
    - Bloomfield, Maurice, 1883 (Box 21, Folder 49)
    - Bodley, Rachel, 1885 (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - Booth, Maude Ballington, 1900 (Box 21, Folder 51)
    - Borg, Selma, 1881 (Box 21, Folder 52)
    - Boutwell, George S., 1854 (Box 21, Folder 53)
    - Bowditch, Henry, 1885 (Box 21, Folder 54)
    - Bowne, Borden Parker, 1890 (Box 21, Folder 55)
    - Boyce, George Price, undated (Box 21, Folder 56)
    - Bradbury, M., 1889 (Box 21, Folder 57)
    - Bradford, 1885, undated (Box 21, Folder 58)
    - Bray, Maria 1881 (Box 21, Folder 59)
    - Brewster, Anna Hampton, 1878 (Box 21, Folder 60)
    - Bridgeman, Laura, undated (Box 21, Folder 61)
    - Bright, Jacob, 1870-71 (Box 21, Folder 62)
    - Bright, John, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 63)
    - Brooks, John Graham, undated (Box 21, Folder 64)
    - Brooks, Philips, 1880-88 (Box 21, Folder 65)
    - Brown, Ford Madox, undated (Box 21, Folder 66)
    - Brownell, W. C., 1871 (Box 21, Folder 67)
    - Bryce, James, 1881 (Box 21, Folder 68)
    - Buchanan, Joseph Rodes, 1890, undated (Box 21, Folder 69)
    - Buck, A.W., 1884-85 (Box 21, Folder 70)
    - Buckel, C. Annette, 1870-87, undated (Box 21, Folder 71)
    - Bumstead, Horace, 1888 (Box 21, Folder 72)
    - Bunsen, George, 1892, undated (Box 21, Folder 73)
    - Burleigh, Charles, undated (Box 21, Folder 74)
    - Burney, Sarah, undated (Box 21, Folder 75)
    - Burroughs, John, 1868, 1890 (Box 21, Folder 76)
    - Butler, Benjamin F., 1865 (Box 21, Folder 77)
    - Butler, H., 1872-82, undated (Box 21, Folder 78)
    - Butler, Josephine, 1877-84 (Box 21, Folder 79)
    - Butler, Lydia, 188? (Box 21, Folder 80)
    - Burdick, Susan, 1840-50, undated (Box 21, Folder 81)
    - Cable, George Washington, 1877-1904 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Cabot, John C., 1877 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Caine, T. Hall, 1887, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Carlyle, H., 1862, 1871 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Carlyle, John A., 1870 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Carlyle, Thomas, 1850 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Carpenter, Philip, 1849 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Cary, Alice, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Chace, Elizabeth Buffum, 1888-90, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Chadwick, John W., 1876-1901 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Champney, Lizzy, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Chandler, Lucinda, 1871 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Channing, Edward, 1884 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Channing, William Ellery, 1838/39 ? (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Channing, William Henry, 1859-83 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Chant, Laura Ormiston, 1888 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Chapman, Maria Weston Chapman, 1844-1885, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Cheney, Ednah Dow, 1889 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Cheney, John, undated (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Child, Lydia Maria, 1860-69, undated (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Child, P.J. 1871 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Churchill, Elizabeth K., 1872-76 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Claflin, Adelaide A., 1893 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Claflin, William, 1869 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Clarke, Anna, 1871 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Clarke, Edward, 1890 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Clarke, James Freeman, 1845-91 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Clarke, Sarah Freeman, 1877-95 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Clinton, Isaiah, 1864 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Clisby, Harriet, 1875 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Cobbe, Frances, n. d. (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Colyer, Vincent, 1856 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Combe, George, 1854 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Connor, Rowland, 1874 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Conway, Moncure Daniel, 1861, undated (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Cooke, George, 1886 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Corelli, Marie, undated (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Cox, Channing H., 1923 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Cranch, Christopher Pearse, 1870-85 (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Cranch, Caroline, undated (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - Crocker, Lucretia, 1870s, undated (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Crosby, Howard, 1889 (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Crowe, Kate Bateman, 1881 (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Cummings, Charles A., 1876 (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Cunningham, Florida, 1891 (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - Curtis, George William, 1855 (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - Dall, Caroline, 1864-90 (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Dana, Richard Henry, 1872-87, undated (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - D'Angerville, Henriette, 1852 (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Deland, Margaret, 1890-93 (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - DeMortie, Louise, 1866 (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - Diaz, Abby Morton, 1882-90, undated (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - Dickerman, Lysander, 1889 (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - Dickinson, Anna E., 1865 (Box 22, Folder 54)
    - Dietrick, Ellen Battelle, 1892 (Box 22, Folder 55)
    - D'Istria, Doria, 1878 (Box 22, Folder 56)
    - Dix, Dorothea, 1896, undated (Box 22, Folder 57)
    - Dogget, Kate and W. E, 1875, undated (Box 22, Folder 58)
    - Douglass, Helen (Mrs. Frederick), 1898 (Box 22, Folder 59)
    - Dufferin (Gov. General of India), 1870 (Box 22, Folder 60)
    - Duncan, I. Matthews, 1871-81 (Box 22, Folder 61)
    - Dwight, John Sullivan, 1881-89 (Box 22, Folder 62)
    - Eastman, Mary F., 1884-89 (Box 22, Folder 63)
    - Easton, John Eaton, 1876-79 (Box 22, Folder 64)
    - Eliot, Josiah, 1792 (Box 22, Folder 65)
    - Elliott, Maud Howe, n. d. (Box 22, Folder 66)
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1862? (Box 22, Folder 67)
    - Evarts, William M., 1876-80 (Box 22, Folder 68)
    - Everett, Edward, 1833-61 (Box 22, Folder 69)
    - Farre, Arthur, undated (Box 22, Folder 70)
    - Farre, Fred I., 1876 (Box 22, Folder 71)
    - Fay, Frank B., 1881-86 (Box 22, Folder 72)
    - Fields, Annie Adams, 1868-99 (Box 22, Folder 73)
    - Fields, Henry, 1887 (Box 22, Folder 74)
    - Fields, James T., 1816-81 (Box 22, Folder 75)
    - Fifield, Emily, 1887-92, undated (Box 22, Folder 76)
    - Fish, Hamilton, 1887 (Box 22, Folder 77)
    - Fiske, John, 1866 (Box 22, Folder 78)
    - Fletcher, Alice, 1879-88 (Box 22, Folder 79)
    - Fletcher, I. Constance, 1879-88 (Box 22, Folder 80)
    - Flint, Charles L., 1871 (Box 22, Folder 81)
    - Forbes, I. W., 1887 (Box 22, Folder 82)
    - Forman, Henry Buxton, 1887-90 (Box 22, Folder 83)
    - Fortel, M., 188l (Box 22, Folder 84)
    - Forten, C.L., 1871 (Box 22, Folder 85)
    - Foster, Abigail Kelly, 1861 (Box 22, Folder 86)
    - French, Daniel Chester, 1882 (Box 22, Folder 87)
    - Frothingham, O.B., 1875-89 (Box 22, Folder 88)
    - Fuller, George, 1882-83 (Box 22, Folder 89)
    - Furnivall, F. J., 1882, undated (Box 22, Folder 90)
    - Gannett, William Channing, 1874-89, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Garrison, Wendell Phillips, 1885 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Garrison, William Lloyd II, 1885-1905 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - George, Henry, 1886-88 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Glyn, Isabella Dallas, 1887 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Goddard, Lucy, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Goodwin, William Watson, 1884-86 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Gosse, Edmund T., 1887 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1889 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Gould, Thomas R., 1881 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Graham, W., 1883? (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Gray, Asa, undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Greeley, Horace, 1856 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Green, William Henry, 1887 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Greene, Edward D. E., 1858 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Greene, Mary A., 1890 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Gregg, James B., 1877 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Gregory, Casper Rene, 1881, 1885 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Greville, Henry, 1892 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Grew, Mary, 1894 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Grey, Earl, 1890 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Griffis, William Elliot, 1887 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Grosvenor, Lord Richard, 1881 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Grimke, Angelina Emily, 1853-54 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Grimke, Sarah M., 1865, undated (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Hagar, Daniel B., 1883 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Hale, Edward Everett, 1854-91 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Hale, Lucretia, undated (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Hale, Susan, undated (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Hall, Granville Stanley, 1885-92, undated: (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Halleck, Fitz Green, 1867 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Hallowell, E. N., 1863 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Hallowell, S.M., 1892 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Hamilton, George, 1893 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Hanaford, Phebe A., 1872 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Hardy, Arthur Sherburne, n. d. (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Hardy, Iza Duffus, 1880 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Harlow, W. G., undated (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Harris, W. T., 1876-94 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Haweis, Francis, 1882, undated (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Hawthorne, Sophia Peabody, 1850s-80 s (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Hayden, Sophia G., 1894 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Hayne, William H., 1887 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Hazen, N.A., 1886 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Henshaw, Samuel, 1891 (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - Herfud, Brooke, 1887 (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1857-1902 (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - Higginson, Waldo, undated (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - Hopkins, E.W., 1882-83, undated (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - Horsford, Eben Norton, 1889 (Box 23, Folder 50)
    - Hosmer, Harriet, undated (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - Houghton, Richard Monckton Milnes (Baron), undated (Box 23, Folder 52)
    - Hovey, Marian, 1892, undated (Box 23, Folder 53)
    - Howard, Oliver Otis, 1881 (Box 23, Folder 54)
    - Howe, Julia Ward, 1862-1900, undated (Box 23, Folder 55)
    - Howe, Mark Anthony Dewolfe, 1887 (Box 23, Folder 56)
    - Howe, Maud, 1885 (Box 23, Folder 57)
    - Howe, Samuel, 1867, undated (Box 23, Folder 58)
    - Howells, William Dean, 1874-94 (Box 23, Folder 59)
    - Hubbard, Stephen A., 1881 (Box 23, Folder 60)
    - Hughes, Ball, undated (Box 23, Folder 61)
    - Hughes, Thomas, 1870 (Box 23, Folder 62)
    - Hunt, Harriot K., 1854-60, undated (Box 23, Folder 63)
    - Hunt, T. Henry, 1887, 1891 (Box 23, Folder 64)
    - Hunt, Margaret, undated (Box 23, Folder 65)
    - Hunt, Seth, 1870 (Box 23, Folder 66)
    - Hunt, William Morris, undated (Box 23, Folder 67)
    - Huntington, D. G., 1881 (Box 23, Folder 68)
    - Huntington, William Edwards., 1894 (Box 23, Folder 69)
    - Hyatt, Alphons, 1886-97 (Box 23, Folder 70)
    - Irby, A.P., 1884 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Ireland, Alexander, 1890 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Jackson, William A., 1864 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Jacobi, Mary Putnam, 1886, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Jacobs, Harriet, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - James, Henry, Sr., undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - James, Lewis, 1896 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Jeffries, B. Jay, n .d. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Jennison, Julie, 1874 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Jerrold, Blanchard, 1858 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Jewett, Sarah Orne, 1890-96, undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Jex-Blake, Sophia, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Johnson, A.E., 1873 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Johnson, Ellen C., 1888-92, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Johnson, Samuel, 1865-85 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Jones, Jenk L., 1873 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Kastner, Charles, 1884 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Kelterborn, Louis, 1890 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Kemble, Fanny, undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Kemble, John Philip, undated (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Kingsman, E., 1865 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Kirkman, Thomas P., 1867 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Knight, Joseph, 1873, 1886 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Knowlton, H. M., 1884 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Knupfer, Benedict, 1847 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Koehler, Sylvester Rosa, 1888 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Kovacs, J., 1887 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Landen, Jean M., n. d. (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Langhorne, Ovid, 1877 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Lanman, Charles R., 1883 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Larcom, Lucy, 1882-92 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Lawton, William C., 1889-90 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Learned, J. C., undated (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Leith, W. L., 1880 (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Leland, Charles G., 1883 (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Lewis, Anna, 1875 (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Lewis, Winslow, 1862 (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Linton, William James, 1870 (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Livermore, J. S., undated (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Livermore, L. J., 1870 (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Livermore, Mary Ashton Rice, 1885-96 (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - Long, John T., 1891-98 (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1864-78 (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - Longfellow, Samuel, undated (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Loring, Charles, 1879-86 (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - Lowell, James Russell, 1885-87 (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - Lowell, Josephine Shaw, 1889 (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - Lucas, Margaret, 1877 (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - McCall, N., 1880, undated (Box 24, Folder 49)
    - McCall, W., 1852 (Box 24, Folder 50)
    - McCarthy, Justin Huntley, 1885-89 (Box 24, Folder 51)
    - McKaye, Eric, undated (Box 24, Folder 52)
    - McKaye, Maria E., undated (Box 24, Folder 53)
    - Nabb, Benjamin Pickman, 1895 (Box 24, Folder 54)
    - Mann, George C., 1894, 1894 (Box 24, Folder 55)
    - Mann, Mary Tyler (Peabody), 1869-84, undated (Box 24, Folder 56)
    - Marlowe, Julia, undated (Box 24, Folder 57)
    - Martin, R. Montgomery, 1840 (Box 24, Folder 58)
    - Martineau, Harriet, 1840-50 (Box 24, Folder 59)
    - May, Abby W., undated (Box 24, Folder 60)
    - May, Samuel J., 1859 (Box 24, Folder 61)
    - Mayo, Amory Dwight, 1861 (Box 24, Folder 62)
    - Mazzini, I., 1862 (Box 24, Folder 63)
    - Mead, Edwin, 1888-1904, undated (Box 24, Folder 64)
    - Millet, Jean Francois, 1858 (Box 24, Folder 65)
    - Millet, Pierre, undated (Box 24, Folder 66)
    - Mills, Charles D.B., 1876-85, undated (Box 24, Folder 67)
    - Mitchell, Edward C., 1887 (Box 24, Folder 68)
    - Mitchell, Maria, 1885-86, undated (Box 24, Folder 69)
    - Moore, C.H. 1871 (Box 24, Folder 70)
    - Moore, Edward, n. d. (Box 24, Folder 71)
    - Moore, Eli, 1860 (Box 24, Folder 72)
    - Monteagle, Lord, 1881 (Box 24, Folder 73)
    - Moore, Rebecca, 1888 (Box 24, Folder 74)
    - Morris, Lewis, 1866 (Box 24, Folder 75)
    - Morse, Alpheus C., 1885, undated (Box 24, Folder 76)
    - Morse, Edward L., 1875-88 (Box 24, Folder 77)
    - Morse, John T., 1886 (Box 24, Folder 78)
    - Morse, L. H., 1876, undated (Box 24, Folder 79)
    - Morse, Samuel Finley Breese, undated (Box 24, Folder 80)
    - Morton, Helen, undated (Box 24, Folder 81)
    - Mosher, Eliza M., 1881 (Box 24, Folder 82)
    - Moulton, Louise Chandler, n. d. (Box 24, Folder 83)
    - Munn, Emily A., 1879 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Murray, Elizabeth, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Murray, James A. H., 1880-90 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Nearing, Scott, 1923 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Newman, Francis, 1869 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Nichol, Elizabeth Pease, 1840 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Niles William H., 1891 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Norman, R. W., 1889 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - North, Edward, 1887 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Norton, Charles Eliot, 1889-90 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Nourse, J. E., 1882 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Oliver, D., 1875 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - O'Molloy, John, 1884 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Oliver Optic see Adams, William T. (Box 25)
    - O'Reilly, John Boyle, 1887 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Owen, Robert Dale, 1863 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Paget, James, 1875-88, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Paine, Robert Treat, 1889 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Palfrey, S.N., 1867 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Palmer, Alice Freeman, 1890 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Parker, Theodore and Lydia, 1859-61, undated (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Parker, Wilson, 1876-77 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Parkes, Bessie R., 1857 (Box 25, Folder 22)